We're going to have the invocation by Ben Loring.
Please pray with me.
Dear Heavenly Father, we humbly come before you.
Thank you for all the blessings that you have bestowed upon us as individuals, as a community, and as a nation.
We pray that as we go through the business of the city this evening, that you guide us, teach us, and inspire us to do your will in Jesus name.
Amen.
Do you like the United States of America?
And do the Republic for which it stands?
One nation, another God, in the middle of the whole political liberty and justice for all.
Number four, public input.
And that's good to personal appearances.
There's none.
Five, consent and agenda.
Staff recommends we approve out of six, three, seven.
Five, eight, except to reject resolution, MSU-A-201-O1 for proposed water and waste water improvements on 69A.
Any questions on that?
I'll make a motion to approve.
Five, nine, discussion and possible action on poll attachment.
Ben Loring.
The normally when the city is assessing a fee of some sort, it's done by an ordinance.
In this particular case, on poll attachments, we do not have an ordinance.
And we've been doing it apparently forever, just by contracts that we're entering into with the individuals.
Because there's not an ordinance on it, we're all over the place on what we do with these contracts.
The reason why this particular item is on the agenda is because integrity.
address needs to run a line from the hospital to over to Main Street, and they're wanting
to attach to our polls in order to do that.
So that was the impetus for this coming up, but in looking at several of the agreements that
we have in the past, for instance, the per poll attachment fee ranges from anywhere from
a dollar fifty to four dollars per poll per year.
And then on some of them, we have annual fees on top of that, the highest being $120,
and the lowest being fifty dollars, and then there's some that there is no annual fee.
So the only one that regularly pays us that has a poll attachment agreement with us
is cable one, apparently there's some that we have agreements with that have not paid us for
some time.
Again, it's just that we're all over the place.
So the long and the short of it is, we need to do an ordinance, and we're going to start
the process of doing that.
But in the meantime, integrist needs approximately, I think it's 10 polls to attach to.
And so we've put together the proposed agreement that you have in front of you.
We need to know if you want an annual fee, we need to know what per poll assessment you want,
but the entire agreement is drafted so that recognizing that we need to do an ordinance,
and once we do that ordinance, then the contract would be redone.
There's a very extensive federal law that applies to this.
Most of our agreements have nothing to do with no mention of it.
They properly drafted agreement that sets out all the requirements of the federal law.
We've got one and it's 36 pages long.
Most of our agreements are one paragraph long.
So we just have, we need some guidance, but we need to do something immediately to help the hospital
out.
cable one re-occurging them $3 a pole no annual fee. We have another agreement with
Intagress and it's $4 a pole and a $120 annual fee. But that one entails five poles
so their total annual figure is $140. And that runs from the hospital to the
professional building is, is my understanding. But they don't pay that one. My understanding
is we haven't built them for a while because we haven't built a lot of these for a while.
They're just not in our system to be consistently done. I don't think they made it into
encode when encode started and it's just never been picked up. So if we'd pass this
order to get an ordinance will they be built? Yes. And they will be consistent one with the
other. Some of these that we believe that there are agreements on, they may not even
be using them. And then I mean, Kelly Carr Company is one of them. I don't think there's
anything there right now. So if we don't add numbers to these blanks, do we leave that up to
Bowen Tyler, who makes those decisions? You can leave that to their discretion. The Bow has
addressed this with Jonas at the hospital. I don't know the details of what's been discussed.
But just really that we were going to be putting it before the council tonight so that they
could move forward to improve their network access. But it would be followed up with the contract.
We would work out the details and he completely understood.
More fee.
Right.
That's what we have to do about when we talk about it.
We have to think about the big picture and what happens with expansion and what happens with
So you get the communication lines to post your left line and that thing.
There we have it.
Right.
But what does that look like to the city take stress in some of the?
There's a?
Okay.
You can't use that point more than we want to do.
I think cable TV's three feet and then talk on it's four feet.
And then there's some fibers in between those two.
Can the ordinance be drafted to where we have the right to make those adjustments as needed?
Or if it became an overcrowding situation?
It undoubtedly it could.
Again, the major thing is we have the federal telecommunications act of 1996 which is apparently a couple
of hundred pages long and I have not read it.
And when I do I probably won't understand it because most of it is going to be in engineering terminology.
But and that's why we have the one contract that is 36 pages long.
So we just need to have some consistency in what we're doing.
That's the bottom line and regularly bill those people that are using our polls.
But in the meantime, integrity needs some help right now.
Drifting that I think will be a relatively major deal unless we can plagiarize the heck out of somebody else's ordinance that we're satisfied.
Really understands what the federal law says.
Well, my opinion we go ahead and let the integrity.
Hang in line.
Absolutely.
Right.
With the understanding that this is coming.
And that's the way this agreement is drafted.
We'll let them do it, but it'll be subject to change once we do the ordinance.
Right.
We have a record of all the ones that we've found, the real skinny ones, so are you looking for a motion for us to allow the tigers to move ahead?
We do need that, they need that, so that's what I would suggest.
If you want to give any guidance on filling in these blanks, or if you want to leave that to Bow and Tyler negotiating with integrists,
that's fine, that's what the motions should say.
Well, I think if we're charging cable one, three bucks with no end of E, and they've actually been paying, then that's probably kind of what we need to land.
Yes?
Yes.
I do think we need to do our homework to figure out what the appropriate rate would be because I think the rate that we're basing this on is pretty old.
Correct.
Yeah, that was done with cable one, I think it was in the probably in the 90s, if not earlier.
Well, how about I make a motion that you can prove that this is the ability to attach this to these holes,
provided that we come up with the movements that you're in to discuss the pressure.
Which is a long motion.
Well, that would be fine, we just need some guidance.
I'll second to 10 staff reports, 11 in the other new business that has risen since the post.
to see this agenda. 12, trustee, community and announcements, I've got a letter here from the
Auto County Free Fair Board and they are thanking the city for their involvement in
the fair and they said that the updates and the efforts made to the fairgrounds and especially
the exhibition building did not go unnoticed. This is the cleanest we have found the facility
we are starting the fair we have had in the many many years. So let's test them to Kevin and his
team for getting the fairgrounds ready to go for these guys and I appreciate it and so I
thank you letter to the city so appreciate you guys anybody else. 13, maybe we'll be continued.